嘿，你们好，我是TheCherno，欢迎回到我的OpenGL系列教程
hey, what's up guys, my name is TheCherno, welcome back to my OpenGL series
那么回顾一下上期视频，我们讲了创建整个测试框架和测试类等等
so we are back last time, we talked about creating this whole test framework and test classes and all that
我们可以创建测试类
and we had something where we could actually create test classes
它扩展了一个Test基类
which extended like kind of a base Test class
我们可以演示每一个单独的OpenGL或特性
and we could kind of demonstrate each individual OpenGL or feature
或者我们想用OpenGL在沙箱中做的任何事
or whatever we wanted to really do with OpenGL in kind of a sandbox
测试环境对我们来说很干净
test environment that was really clear for us to kind of
我想，演示并拥有我们在OpenGL中学到的各种特性的例子
I guess, demonstrate and have samples of the various features that we learned about in OpenGL
还有各种各样的图形测试
and just various kind of under graphical tests
那就是我们将来要用到的东西
that's the kind of stuff that we're going to use for in the future
所以如果你们还没看过那个视频，一定要去看看
so if you haven't seen that video, then if we check that out
因为今天我们要扩展那个
because today we're going to be extending that
上次我给你们布置了一些作业，为了搞明白
and last time I gave you guys a bit of homework to figure out
我们如何创建某种测试菜单，我们在哪儿可以点击一个测试
how we could create some kind of test menu, where we could click on a test
它就会构造一个新的测试，然后当我们回到主菜单
and it would construct a new test, and then when we went back to the main menu
它就会删除那个测试
it would kind of delete that test
卸载所有资源，然后再次呈现给我们测试菜单
unload all the resources, and then kind of present us with that test menu again
今天我将向你们展示其中一种实现它的方法
and today I'm going to show you one of the ways that we can actually implement this
所以，感谢所有分享他们解决方案的人
so thank you to all of those people who share their solutions
我想大多数人会在discord分享
I think most of them will share it on discord
所以如果你们喜欢我的discord，那就是discord
so if you guys have enjoyed my discord, that is discord
不好意思，是TheCherno.com/discord，那是邀请链接
sorry, so TheCherno.com/discord, and then that's kind of the invite link
这是一个很棒的社区，你们可以在这里谈论
it's just a great community of people where you can talk about
各种编程开发图像游戏的方面
all kind of aspects of programming developing graphics games
不管你们想讨论什么，所有的东西都在那里
whatever it is you want to talk about, all that stuff is there
所以一定要加入这个社区，如果你们还没有加入的话
so definitely join that community, if you haven't already, anyway
让我们进入到代码吧，并检查我们创建那个测试菜单的方法
let's just have into some code, and check out a way for us to create that test menu
让它为我们构造和销毁类实例，好了
and have it kind of construct and destruct class instances for us, okay
那么进入Application,cpp文件
so jumping into the Application.cpp file that we have
顺便说一句，如果你们还没获得这个代码的话
if you guys don't have access to this yet, by the way
一定要去访问patreon.com/TheCherno帮助支持这个系列
definitely go to patreon.com/TheCherno help support this series
它真的能帮助我为你们制作了更多的视频
it really does help me make more videos for you guys
并且你们也会在github上收到每一期单独提交的代码
and you'll also receive all of the code kind of episode by episode as separate commit on github
所以一定要去看看那个，帮助支持这个系列
so definitely check that out and help support the series
这是从测试框架一期开始的代码
this is the code from the beginning of the test framework episode
如果我们看看我们这里有什么
and if we take a look at what we have here
本质上我们已经有了这个test，它演示了这个TestClearColor
essentially we already have this test, that were kind of presenting this TestClearColor
但我要做的是首先到这个tests文件夹，添加一个新项
but what I'm actually going to do is start off by just going to this testsfolder, and adding a new item
这实际上是，你们知道的，我们不需要创建新文件之类的
and it's going to be actually, you know, what we didn't have to create a new file
我们也可以在Test.h头文件中做这个，只需要一个cpp文件
we're just going to do this in the Test.h header file, and we will need a cpp file
因为我想分离实现，所以我将创建一个名为Test.cpp的cpp文件
because I do want to separate the implementation, so I will create a cpp file called Test.cpp
这里，在C++命名空间中，我要创建这个TestMenu
and over here, in C++ name space, I'm going to create this TestMenu
这个TestMenu类会有，它确实只是一个测试
and this TestMenu class is going to have, it's just going to be a test really
所以如果我们在这里实现或扩展Test类
so if we implement or rather extend the Test class here
并且然后我们会得到所有这些东西，我把它复制粘贴到这里
and then we'll have pretty much all of this stuff, so I'll just copy and paste that over here
我不会实现这个，我只会标记为override，override，override
I won't implement this, and I'll just mark it as override, override and override
顺便说一下，关于这个很酷的事情是，因为我没有让它们成为纯虚函数
the cool thing, about this, by the way, is that because I didn't make them pure virtual functions
我们把这个去掉，因为我没有把它们写成纯虚函数
let's get rid of this, because I didn't make them pure virtual functions
我们不需要重写其他的，我们不需要
we don't actually have to override other ones, we don't need
这是一个很好的例子，我想在下面的评论中有人会问
so this is a great example, I think someone asked in the comments below
为什么我不让这些函数是纯虚函数的呢
why I didn't make these functions pure virtual
如果我像这样写一个等于0，我就会这样做，我留下它们的原因
and I would do that if I just write an equals zero like this, the reason I kind of left them
作为一个特殊的函数，用一个像这样的空白函数体来实现它们
as just special functions and implemented them with a blank body like this
它说的是，我们可以有选择地选择哪些是我们自己想要实现的
it said that we could selectively choose which ones we actually wanted to implement ourselves
如果它们等于0，如果它们都是纯虚函数，我就必须把三个函数全部实现
if they were equal zero, if they were all pure virtual, I'd have to have all three
但在这个方法中，我不需要onUpdate或onRender，所以我不需要它们
but with this method, I don't actually want onUpdate or onRender, so I don't need to have them
我可以直接删除它们，然后一切仍然正常
I can just go ahead and delete them, and then everything will still work fine
我不需要实现它们，这只是给我的一个选项
I don't have to implement them, it's just an option that's given to me
所以这个TestMenu类会做两件事
so this TestMenu class is going to do two things
首先，它将包含我们所有测试的集合
first of all, it's going to contain a collection of all of our tests
并且我们想要找到一种方法，能够给它们起一个特定的名字
and we want a way to be able to basically I guess present them with a specific name
所以我们需要一个指向Test类的指针
so we need a pointer to a Test class
一个Test实例，我猜，一个Test对象实例
a Test instance, I guess, a Test object instance
但我还想存储一个我们可以提供Test的名称
but I also want to store a name that we can provide the Test
所以那就是出现在测试菜单中的按钮标签
so that's kind of the label, I guess, that appears for our button in the test menu
所以我要做的是放一个std::pair的向量
so what I'm going to do is put a vector of std::pair
我们会有一对字符串和实际的Test指针，像这样
and we're going to have a pair of string and the actual Test pointer like this
现在这是它变得有点有趣的地方，我实际上不想要一个Test指针
now here's where it gets a little bit interesting, I don't actually want a Test pointer
因为那意味着实例已经存在，这很好
because that implies that the instance already exists, which would be great
如果我们采取这样的策略
if we kind of went with the strategy of
我只想在应用程序的开始创建我所有的测试
I just want to create all of my tests at the beginning of my application
然后把它们添加到我的菜单上，然后切换到它们可能会激活它们
and then add them to my menu, and then like switching to them would activate them maybe
但我并不想那么做
but I don't actually want to do that
因为我做得对的是我有了构造函数和析构函数
because what I'm doing right is I've got my construction and destructor
所以我真正想要发生的是当我按下按钮
so what I actually want to happen is when I press the button
我不希望它只是激活一个Test实例
I don't want it to just activate a Test instance
我实际上想创建一个Test实例，从字面上来说，也就是new Test()
I actually wanted to create a Test instance, I literally wanted to say, new Test
并且当我退出那个测试时，我需要删除这个测试
and when I kind of go back out of that test, I wanted to delete the test
所以我不能只添加一个Test指针，因为Test指针
so I can't just add a Test pointer, because Test pointer
当然是因为一个指向已经存在对象的指针
of course would be a pointer to an already existing object
我需要的是一种方法来构建那个对象
what I need instead is a way to construct that object
一种我可以做我正在做的事情的方法
and one way that I could do that which I'm
我现在要做的是我可以给它提供一个lambda
what I'm going to do now here is I could actually just provide it with a lambda
我可以为它提供一个函数来构造我的Test类
I could provide it with a function that constructs that that Test class of mine
那么，如果我们回到这里，我将创建这一对中的第二个元素
so, if we go back here, I'm gonna make the second element of the pair here
一个std::function，只有Test指针，没有参数
an std::function of just Test pointer here, and no parameters
所以这基本上意味着
so this basically means that
这个函数返回一个Test指针，不接受任何参数
this function returns a Test pointer, and does not take any parameters
所以这基本上会返回new Test，这取决于我们实际创建的是哪个测试
so this is basically going to return new Test, depending on which test we actually create
并且那就是为什么要用向量，现在我要叫这个Test
and then that's gonna be why vector, and now I'm gonna call this Test
好了，那么这里我还需要一个角括号
okay, so I need one more angular bracket here
我会包括functional，这样我就能访问std函数的注解
and I'll include functional, so that I get access to the std function gloss
好的，很好，我们有了，我有了一个成对的向量，每一对包含一个字符串
okay cool, so there we go I've got a, I've got a vector of pairs, and each pair contains a string
以及一个返回测试指针的函数，不带参数，好了
and a function which returns a test pointer, and takes no parameters, okay
所以我可以创建一个struct，而不是创建一个nacity pair
so I could have created a struct, instead of creating a nacity pair
但这实际上是相当微不足道的
but this is actually rather trivial
我不想在新结构中创建一个全新的类型
I don't really want to create a whole new type in a new struct
我不知道，我不知道什么时候我叫它Test，有人得了Test
called like, I don't know, Test, I don't know when I call it somebody got test
可能像testMenu实例或类似的东西，我不确定
so maybe like testMenu instance or something like that, I'm not sure
没有必要装饰这样的东西，我们可以保持匿名，因为我们知道这里
there's no need to decorate anything like that, we can keep it kind of anonymous, because we know here
这基本上就是收集一个字符串向量的列表
that basically this is just collect a list right a vector of strings
还有那些字符串创建的实际测试类
and the actual test classes which those those strings kind of create
因为字符串是空的，因为我们想给按钮一个标签
because the string is just bare, because we want to give our button a label
当我们在屏幕上看到它时，这一点是有意义的
this little makes sense when we actually see it on the screen
很好，我想要的另一个东西是指向currentTest的指针
okay cool, and then one other thing I actually want is a pointer to the currentTest
我们需要这个的原因是因为我们的菜单
now the reason we need this is because our menu is
改变当前应用中活动的currentTest
going to change the currentTest that's active right now in application
我们没有currentTest，我们只有这个
we don't have a currentTest, we've just got this
我在这里要做的是有一个实际的Test指针，这是我们的currentTest
what I'm actually going to do here is have an actual Test pointer, which here's our currentTest
好了，我就叫它currentCurrent，这是我们需要修改的
okay, I was called currentCurrent, this is what we actually need to modify
我们希望测试菜单能帮我们做到这一点
and we want the test menu to actually do that for us
现在我们可以传入一些lambds或其他东西来修改这个
now we could again pass in some kind of lambds or something which modifies this
但一个更简单的方法是传递一个对那个Test指针的引用
but an easier way is going to be just to pass in a reference to that Test pointer
然后这个testMenu将能够写到那个指针
and then this testMenu is actually going to be able to write to that pointer
从而改变currentTest，在这里的构造函数中传递它
and thus change the currentTest, so in the constructor here passing that
我想我们会调用一个currentTest指针
I guess we'll call a currentTest pointer
如果我们点击这里，我们回到那个c++文件
and then if we right click here, actually let's go back to that C++ file
我可以包含Test.h，我们会放入命名空间tests
so I can include Test.h, we'll put in namespace tests
然后我们可以回到这里，实现我们需要的所有方法
and then we can go back here, and implement everything we need
通过创建方法实现，很好，我不认为我们需要析构函数
by creating the method implementations, okay cool, I don't think we need a destructor actually
因为所有东西都在堆栈上，不管怎样我都要去掉它
because everything's stacked, I'll get rid it anyway
这样我们就可以去掉析构函数了
so we can get rid of that destructor
这很好，它绝对是我想要的
and then this is great, it definitely do what I want
这是因为它是test名称空间，而不是tests，所以去掉它，然后实现那个
that's because it's the test namespace not tests, so get rid of that, and do that
好了，那么构造函数，这里会像这样设置当前测试为currentTest指针
okay, so constructor, there's gonna set current test to currentTest pointer like that
然后OnImGuiRender会渲染我们拥有的列表
and then OnImGuiRender is going to actually render that list that we have
那么就是for auto，这是测试中的test
so I'll just say for auto, and this will be I guess test in our tests
我们要做的是创建一个渲染和ImGui按钮
what we're going to do is actually create a render and ImGui button
这里发生了什么，icd，不，我们需要包含一个向量
that was okay what's going on here icd no, okay, so we need to include a vector
在这个测试中，我们会渲染ImGUI按钮
oops, okay, so inside this test, we're going to basically render ImGUI button
我们会说ImGui::Button()，标签将是那个测试
so we'll say ImGUI button label is going to be that test
对于你们来说，这是个元组，所以就是test.first
this is a paire for you guys, so test.first
这只是一个点视觉辅助，谢谢
and this will just be a dot visual assist thank you
.c_str()，因为它需要一个c字符串，当它指向字符指针时
dot c_str(), because it wants a c string once it comes to char pointer
当然，如果按钮被按下
and then of course if that button is pressed
我们想要执行那个按钮说要做的和那个按钮
we basically want to execute what that button says to do and that button
这个按钮要做的就是这个功能
what that button says to do is that actual function
我们只需要像这样调用test.second()，因为这是我们想要执行的函数
so we really just need to call test.second() like that, because it's the function we want to execute
现在我们不需要调用它了
now we don't just need to call it
这个返回，记住，这个返回一个Test指针，这个返回一个新的Test指针
this returns, remember, this returns a Test pointer, this returns the new Test pointer
它应该会为我们构造，这也是我们想要设置的currentTest
that it's supposed to construct for us, so that's what we actually want to set currentTest too
那么currentTest被设置为构建我们实际测试类实例
so currentTest gets set to that lander that constructs our actual test class instance
我们实际上还没有创造出那种功能的lambda
we haven't actually created that lambda yet that function
但是马上，让我们包含，我要在这里，因为我们需要
but will in a second, let's include, I am going here, because we need to
很好，这对我来说很好，我们有，我们应该有一个按钮列表
okay cool, there we go, so that looks pretty good to me, so we've got we should have a list of buttons
如果我们按下按钮，那么它会改变currentTest指针
and if we press the button, then it will hopefully change that currentTest pointer to be whatever
这个测试实际上作为它的创建函数返回
this test actually returns as its kind of creation function
很好，这看起来很好，让我们创建那个TestMenu
okay cool, that looks pretty good to me, let's go ahead and create that TestMenu
我将在这里也包含它，所以实际上它应该已经被包含了
I'll go ahead and include it over here as well, so actually it should already be included
因为它在Test.h文件中，我们看看
because it's in the Test.h file, so let's see
TestMenu menu = new test::TestMenu()
TestMenu menu equals new test testMenu
我们会传入这个currentTest
we're going to pass in this currentTest
我将叫这个currentTest，这样更明确一些
I'll actually call this currentTest, just so that it's a bit more explicit
默认情况下，我们会将这个able设为null，然后当它在这里被创建时
by default, we'll set this able to null, and then when it does get created over here
我们会设置currentTest = menu，因为我们想从菜单开始
we'll set the currentTest equal to menu, because we wanted to basically start off with the menu
现在从这点来说，你们可以添加一些命令行参数或类似的东西
now at this point, you could add some kind of command line argument or something like that
如果你们希望这个应用程序已经用一个特定的测试启动
if you wanted this application to boot up already with a specific test
这是非常有用的，如果你们尝试测试什么东西的话
this is very useful, if you're actually trying to test something
因为如果你们真的在做测试或者在研究新的OpenGL技术之类的
because if you're actually working on a test or working on a newer OpenGL technique or something
或者尝试去实现一些东西，不管它是什么，它被实现为一个测试
or trying to implement something whatever it is, and it's implemented as a test
你们不希望每次都有菜单出现，然后你们必须点击它
you don't want to have the menu come up every time, and then you have to click on it
所以每次你们调试代码的时候，菜单就会出现
so every time you do bug your code, menu comes up
然后你们必须点击菜单，必须点击，这是浪费时间
then you have to click on it menu comes up, have to click, that's a waste of time
所以你们可以从一开始就用它来做测试
so you can just get it to kind of open a test for you kind of from the get go
不用先去看菜单
without having to go first to the menu
而不是硬编码，这只是一个特定的测试或其他
and instead of hard codingm, that to just go to a specific test or whatever
你们可以把它作为一个命令行参数
you could just have it as a command line argument
那很好，如果你们也在一个团队中工作的话
that's really nice, if you're working in a team as well
因为这意味着
because it means that instead of
你们不小心签入了为特定测试设置测试的代码
you accidentally checking in the code that sets the test for specific test
你们正在处理的那个，你们可以把它作为命令行参数
the one that you're working on, you can just have it as a command line argument
这个绝对是存储在你们的用户设置中
which is definitely stored kind of in your user settings
这样就不会真正提交到这个项目中
and thus wouldn't actually be committed to the project
如果你们喜欢，你们可以做一些这样的事情
so yeah you could do something like that if you like
那可以成为一个很好的家庭作业
that could be a nice homework task
所以，让它，接受一个测试者的命令行参数的名称
so make it, take in the name of a tester's command line argument
打开它，如果那个命令行参数真的被设置了
and open that in maybe if that's actually, if that command line argument is actually set
很好，现在我们不用担心这个清除颜色测试
okay cool, so we won't worry about this test clear color just yet
现在我们把所有东西都预热
now we operating everything on the heat here by the way
因为我们确实想要探索删除之类的东西
because we do want to explore the deletion and all that stuff
所以这个测试清除颜色或其他的东西会在一分钟内改变
so this test clear color or whatever will kind of change in a minute
让我们先确保它能工作，我们没有办法添加测试
let's just make sure this works first, we have no way to actually add tests
我知道我们马上就会解决这个问题，但我想先把这个设置好
and I'm aware of that we'll fix that in a minute, but I want to set this up first
基本上我们要做的就是当我们开始新帧时
basically all we're going to do is when we start the new frame
我们会说如果currentTest不正确，因此，如果currentTest
we're going to say if the currentTest is not now right, so if currentTest
然后我们基本上会更新currentTest并渲染currentTest
then we're going to basically update the currentTest and render the currentTest
然后我们会开始我们的ImGui窗口它会被称为test
and then we're going to begin our ImGui window which is going to be just called test I guess
我们可以把测试的名字分开
which is going to be we could actually separate the name of the test
但我们会把它作为测试对象，我们会把我们的deltaTime取为0
but we'll keep it as just test for now on object, we'll take in zero I guess is our deltaTime
然后这实际上会调用一个currentTest->OnRender
and then this is actually what's going to call currentTest OnRender
不好意思，是ImGuiRender
oh sorry ImGuiRender
现在我们要实现我讲过的那个后退按钮
now we are going to have to implement that back button that I talked about
让我们直接去实现那个吧
let's go ahead and do that now actually
如果currentTest不是menuTest，它不等于menu
so if our currentTest is not the menuTest, so it doesn't equal menu
它可能叫testMenu或者类似的东西testMenu
which probably call it testMenu or something like that testMenu
为了不让大家太困惑，我喜欢命名变量为有意义的东西
just so that we're not too confused here, I like to call my variables meaningful things
即使这意味着使它们更长，我们就叫它testMenu
even if it does mean making them longer, so we'll call this testMenu
如果currentTest不等于testMenu
so if the so if the currentTest is not testMenu
然后就是ImGui::Button，我想我们先画一个返回箭头
and ImGui::Button, I guess we'll just draw a back arrow for now
我们会画一个ImGui按钮，我不能把这个箭头画反了
so basically we're going to draw an ImGui button, I can't play factory that backwards
我们会画一个ImGui按钮，那就是我们的返回箭头，但这只会发生
we're going to draw an ImGui button which is our back arrow, but that's only going to happen
如果测试在测试菜单中，我可以嵌套这些if语句
if the test is in test menu right, so I could nest these if statements
但我只是用和运算符把它们放在一起，这意味着
but I've just added them kind of side by side with an and operator which means of course
如果这个值为假，这个条件甚至不会被求值
this condition won't even be evaluated, if this is false
如果currentTest不是testMenu
so if the currentTest is not testMenu
那么我们会绘制这个按钮，如果按钮被点击
then we'll draw this button, and if that button is clicked
然后我们就进入了这个阶段
and that's when we get into this stage
我们要做的是删除currentTest，然后设置currentTest = testMenu
so what we want to do is delete the currentTest, and then set the currentTest equal to testMenu
差不多了，很好，现在我们有办法回到我们的测试菜单
and that is pretty much it, okay cool, so now we have a way to get back to our test menu
我们现在真正需要的是一种创建测试的方法，对吧
really all we need now is a way to actually create kind of tests right
所以我要做的就是添加一个函数
so the way I want to do that is I'm actually going to add a function
我要把代码写得好像函数已经存在一样
and I'm actually going to kind of write the code as if the function exists already
许多人问我
a lot of people ask me
这是写复杂代码的好方法，我刚写了一个正确的代码
what a good way to write kind of marginally complex code I just had a right code really
当你们不确定的时候，比如，你们不想开始运行一个函数
when you're kind of not sure of like you know, you don't want to just start running a function
因为你们不确定它应该返回什么，你们取的是什么代词
because you're not really sure what it's supposed to return what pronoun is it you take
最好的方法就是假装这个函数已经存在
the best way to do that is just to pretend that the function already exists
从使用这个函数开始，在这种情况下，我要假装这个函数存在
and just actually start by using the function, so in this case, I'm going to pretend that function exists
在测试菜单中，我要写testMenu->RegisterTest
and into test menu I'm going to just write testMenu arrow RegisterTest
现在我想注册测试，我需要传递类型
now I want to register the test, I need to pass them the types
这显然将是一个模板，所以我想注册TestClearColor
this is clearly going to be a template, so I want to register the TestClearColor
然后我当然想给它一个名字，所以我会用一个参数
and then of course I want to give it a name, so I'll just use a parameter for that
我把它命名为，我不知道，清除颜色之类的吧，对吧
and I'll call it, I don't know, clear color or something like that right
那就是我们的清除颜色测试，这就是我想让函数做的
that's gonna be our clear color test, that is now what I want the function to do okay
我现在知道函数需要是模板需要接受类型
I now know the function needs to be a template needs to take in the type
它还需要接收测试的名称，以便它可以在测试菜单中显示它
it needs to also take in the name of the test, so that it can display it in the test menu right
因为我们有测试菜单，它把那些名字显示为按钮标签
because we have our test menu which displays those names as the button label
当然，实际的函数需要创建一个lambda
and then of course the actual function needs to create a lambda
创建此类类型的新实例
that creates a new instance of this class type
所以从现在开始就很简单了，因为我已经创建了函数
so it's really straightforward from now basically because I've already created the function
我现在只需要实现它，它将是模板类型名T
I just need to implement it now, so it's gonna be template typename T
它会是一个名为RegisterTest的void函数，接受一个const string
it's gonna be a void function called RegisterTest going to take in a const string
我想我们可以只接受一个const char指针，但我们存储在一个字符串
I guess we can just take in a const char pointer, we are storing at a string though
所以我想我们可以用一个字符指针
so I guess we could take in a char pointer
因为我们知道这个实际上我要渲染一个char指针
because of course we know that this actually this I'm going thing renders a char pointer
但我把它转换成字符串，这也很好
but I am converting it into a string, which is also fine
因为我们可能想做一些nicolation之类的
because we might want to do some nicolation or whatever
我们应该使用字符串，所以我还是把它保留在这里
and we should be using strings anyway, so I'll still keep that here
然后所有这些做的就是把那个test添加到那个列表中
and then all this is really going to do is add that test into that list
所以只要m_Tests.push_back
so just m_Tests.push_back
现在我们要在这里创建一对，所以是make_pair
now we're going to have to make a pair here, so make_pair
我们会传入那个名字，然后我们会创建一个非常简单的lambdas
we're going to pass in that name, and then we're going to just create a very simple lambdas
不需要捕获任何变量，它只会返回new T
doesn't need to capture any variables, that's just going to return new T
就是那样，因为T是我们实际创建的类的类型，好了
and that's it, because T is the type of class that we're actually creating, okay
接下来会发生的是
and then what's going to happen is of course
当我们用我们创建的各种不同的测试类型调用这个注册测试类时
as we call this register test class with every kind of different test type that we create
编译器会在代码库中创建这个注册测试函数的新版本
the compiler is just going to create a new version of this register test function in our code base
那实际上会返回我们请求的基于类型的新类实例，好了
that actually returns the new kind of class instance that we requested based on the type, okay
我要做的一件事就是快速地编写我们的注册测试
one thing I will do is just quickly write for our sanity registering test
然后我们会打印出名字
and then we'll kind of print the name
只是想知道，我们实际上创建了哪些测试
just because it would be nice to know, which tests we actually kind of create
我想我们不会真正创建，而是注册
I guess we'll not really create but register
因为我们会延迟创建直到我们运行lambda
because of course we're deferring the creation until we run the lambda
当我们按下按钮来创建它时，我们正在运行这个lambda
and we're running that lambda when we actually press that button to create it
因为它在这里运行，希望这一切都有用
because it gets run right over here, hopefully all this is making sense
给你们看这个的视频，一定要看关于lambdas的那个视频
playing videos for you guys to watch about this, definitely watch the one on lambdas
我把它的链接放到这里，因为这样就能解释lambda的工作原理了
I'll have it linked up there, because that of course is going to explain how lambdas work
以及我们创建的这些函数是如何被调用的
and how these kind of functions that we're creating that are getting called later
这整个东西是如何工作的呢
how that whole thing works also templates another good video to watch
看看我的C系列c++系列
so in fact just check out my C series C++ series
如果你们不知道这些东西是什么
if you're not kind of sure what some of these things are
因为我想我可能已经掌握了，我在这个系列视频中用到的所有东西
because I have I think I've probably pretty much everything I'm using in this video in that series
好了，所以我们已经准备好了，我们不需要再创建这个了
okay, so we are pretty much good to go, we don't need to create this anymore at all
因为记住，当我们按下按钮时，它会被创建，所以我们把这些都删掉
because remember that actually gets created when we press the button, so let's get rid of all this
我想我实现了所有的东西，我不确定，因为显然我在这里是直播撸码
I think I've implemented everything, I'm not sure, because obviously I'm running the code right here live
那么让我们按f5，看看会发生什么，那是我经常说的
so let's just hit f5, and see what happens, that's I say that very often
让我们点击f5，看看会发生什么，我应该把那个印在t恤上
let's just hit it f5 and see what happens, I should get that on a t shirt
好的，很好，我们有这个测试，我们有清除颜色
okay cool, so we have this test we have clear color
然后希望如果我点击清除颜色
and then hopefully if I press clear color
看看它打开的清除颜色测试，我们可以改变所有的清除颜色
look at that it opens the clear color test shows us how clear color we can change all of that
一切都很好，然后回到点击栏测试
everything works pretty good I think, and then if I go back, we go back to the clickbar test
在这个例子中，你们可以看到它并没有改变快速的颜色
now in this case, you can see it hasn't actually changed the quick color
这让我觉得也许它没起作用，但我很确定它有我很确定发生过的事
which makes me think maybe it hasn't worked, but I'm pretty sure it has what I'm pretty sure has happened
因为你们可以看到它会返回是因为我们没有设置清除颜色
because you can see it does go back is that we're just not setting the clear color
那么回到这里，我们有没有办法在渲染器中设置清除颜色
so if we go back here, and do we have a way to set the clear color inside the renderer
我不认为我们需要，我们已经清楚了
I don't think we do, we've just got clear right
那么在clear中，我们可以添加另一个函数setClearColor
so maybe into clear, we could maybe add another function called setClearColor
然后这个需要我们有一个数学库
and then this would take in we have a math library
我们没有数学库，好吧，好吧，这太难了
we don't have a math library, okay great, okay, this is gonna be too hard
我现在就想做这个，那么回到Application.cpp
and I really want to do this right now, so if we go back to Application.cpp, we're just going to
当我们清除颜色时，我们会把颜色设置为黑色
when we clear the color, we're just going to set the color to black
那么就是glClearColor(0, 0, 0, 1)
so glClearColor zero and zero zerpa and 0 0 and we'll set the alpha tool one
就像那样，测试结束后，我们应该会看到它回到黑色
just like that, okay, so now hopefully, we should see that go back to black, when we go out of the test
因为那就是它的原理
because that's how it should work
很好，如果我们点击清除颜色，我们回到这里我们回到清除颜色
okay cool, so if we click clear color, we go there we go back, it takes our back to clear color
如果有一个额外的测试来测试它，看看它是否能正常工作，那就太棒了
now it'll be fantastic, if we had an additional test to actually test this out, and see if it works properly
但是我们会讲到那个，随着我们开始实现更多的测试
but we're going to kind of get into that, as we start implementing more tests
纹理测试之类的
the texturing tests and all that
我想，下一期，我可能会做一些测试
I think next episode, I'm probably going to create a bunch of tests
把我们现在学过的所有概念都分成不同的测试
and kind of divide out and all the kind of concepts that we've learned right now into separate tests
所以随着我们继续学习OpenGL系列，我们会添加越来越多的测试
so as we continue on with the OpenGL series, we will be adding more and more tests
但是你们可以看到这个框架的基础已经建立并运行了
but you can see the kind of the basis of the framework is up and running
你们可以添加多个测试到这个东西，并且它们就会出现在那个菜单中
you can just add multiple tests to this thing and you'll have them all nicely appeared menu
它们应该在创造中被创造出来，就像点击按钮，然后销毁
and they should be created upon creation upon like actually clicking the button and then destroyed
而我们现在，有一点内存泄漏
when we just right now, there is a little bit of a memory leak
当然，因为我们没有删除testMenu或类似的东西
of course, because we don't delete the testMenu or anything like that
所以我们现在要做的是
so what we actually need to do here is what I want to do is
当我们真正关闭应用程序时，我需要删除currentTest
I need to delete the currentTest, when we actually close the application
你们当然可以这么说
now you could argue that of course
如果我们关闭应用程序，操作系统当然会清理干净
if we do close the application, of course the operating system's going to clean up
不管怎样，我们不需要自己做
anyway, so we don't really need to do it ourselves
但是为了友好起见，我们还是应该在技术上做
however to be nice, it we should still technically do it
所以我要做的是删除currentTest，当我们关闭应用时
so what I'm going to do is delete the currentTest, when we actually close the application
那么当然，当它的while循环结束时
so of course, when it's while loop terminates
glfwWindowShouldClose的while循环，while循环
the while loop that is the glfwWindowShouldClose, while loop
然后我们开始关闭所有东西并终止它，实际要写delete currentTest
then we start to shut everything down and terminate it, I'm actually going to write delete currentTest
事情是这样的，当然这个需要在这个范围内
now here's the thing, and of course this needs to be in this scope
这里是一件事，我还想删除testMenu
here's a thing, I also want to delete the testMenu
然而，如果currentTest是testMenu，我将删除它两次
however if the currentTest is the testMenu, I'll be deleting things twice
如果currentTest不等于testMenu
so if currentTest does not equal testMenu
然后我们会删除testMenu，否则，currentTest已经是testMenu
then we're going to delete testMenu, otherwise, currentTest already is the testMenu
这就是我要删除它的东西，这样我们就不会因为这个代码而崩溃
and that's what I need to delete it, so we shouldn't get any crashes with this code
我们按f5，看看能做什么，如果我们现在就关闭它
let's just hit f5, and see what we can do here, so if we just close it right now
我们应该没问题，因为它只是删除颜色测试，也就是testMenu
we should be fine, because it just deletes the color test, which is the testMenu
然后再按f5运行一下
and then if we hit f5 again
然后我们要进行那个测试，如果我们现在关闭它
then we're going to go into that test and if we close it now
它应该同时删除currentTest和testMenu
it should kind of delete both the currentTest and the testMenu
因为currentTest不是testMenu的话
because the currentTest isn't a long a testMenu
好了，无论如何，我希望你们喜欢这期视频
okay, anyway, I hope you guys enjoyed this video
如果你们喜欢的话，那就为它点赞吧
if you did, you can hit that like button
你们也可以访问patreon.com/TheCherno表达你们的支持
you can also show your support by going to patreon.com/TheCherno
这是访问我今天写的所有代码的好方法
great way to get access to all the code of course that I wrote today
还有其他期的代码
and all of the other episodes as well
像往常一样，向我所有可爱的支持者们大声喊出来
huge shout out as always to all of my lovely supporters
因为如果没有你们，这些视频就不会出现在这里
because these videos would not be here, without you guys
所以我真的很感谢你们，你们的支持对我来说意义重大
so I really am thankful for that, and your support means a lot to me
下次再见，我会继续写这些测试
I will see you guys next time, I'm going to continue writing these tests
下次我会为纹理写一个，当然，从那以后
I'm going to write one for textures next time, and then from then on, of course
我们可以开始学习更多关于OpenGL的知识，会有一个单独的测试类
we can start learning more about OpenGL, and we'll have kind of a separate test class
展示我们学过的所有东西，所以如果我真的很感兴趣的话
demonstrating all the stuff we learn kind of paraps, so if I'm really excited about that
下次见，拜
I'll see you guys next time, goodbye